[BLANK_AUDIO]
Those who weren't from usury stand like when it was struck by the devil's touch.
This is because they claim their usury is a form of trade.
The God permits straight and driven usury.
Whoever he is, this,
abolition from the Lord is a state of usury,
makes use of his fast-running and his judgment with God.
I said, "Those who return are usury,
"they will deserve God,
"or they will be a, they will abide forever."
God diminishes usury and augments charity.
And God just likes to guilty disbelievers.
This is-- and everybody's heard about high interest rates.
This is what's killing this country.
We could just see the crisis.
We're in now 17%, 18%.
So we're being punished for this vicious cycle of inflation.
And wages go off and inflation goes off.
And it's all-- everybody recognizes
that it's tied to use rate.
And this is one of the strongest statements
against something in the corner.
It struck by the devil's touch.
Some of the other things that are forbidden of alcohol gambling
is even pointed out that maybe some good in them.
There's absolutely no good that can come at all from you,
sir.
Only evil.
And this great story.
God diminishes usury and augments charity.
So here we have in the middle of the section
charity something about about you
they're the opposite of each other one of the means that now not only do you
give a man money not only do you want it back but you want more of it back then
you gave it charity means you're giving man money and you don't even want it back
So, forget about it.
So, it's economic.
It's the underlying economic philosophy of Islam.
I think it's given right here in this I.
The trade is permitted.
User is permitted.
But our capitalist society is based on borrowing money
with the idea that you borrow money from somebody
who's got it, an interest.
With the idea that through your trading,
you're gonna make more money and be able to repay it.
We can't see the result, it's just disastrous.
So, really in between the one extreme
of having no free trade, which is what communism is,
and having free trade with usury,
we have what's sometimes been called socialism,
where you have free trade, but the basics of the society
are provided for.
So you can have free trade, and you
don't have to worry about usury.
So it's, for me, an indication of Islam
is based on a type of socialism.
Socialism permits free trade, but it doesn't permit
excessive wealth.
It's only through usury that we have this excessive wealth.
Now people are in a position that they can make more money
through usury than they can through
and flying people and starting businesses.
Instead of, you can make 20% loaning your money out.
It is no risk because you've got to guarantee
piece of paper.
It's better to do that than to set up a business
and employ people to make the same amount of money.
So it's a role disaster.
And all the different problems in this country
are very rich.
It's interesting.
When you buy a house, it's $50,000 for example.
When you calculate after 30 years of paying for it, it's interest and everything, the actual price is $150,000.
50,000. So what did the 100,000 go? 100,000 were gone to employees and salaries and tall
buildings. The skyscrapers never said it. Our home federal savings, being my savings
and associates, I had some great Western bank.
I take this myself to the extreme that I don't like to walk in the banks. I have no bank
accounts I get paid by a paycheck I usually go to the drive-in window that's
the closest I like to get to them. They seem to me that banks are great
houses of sin. Worse than tablets because after all alcohol is supposed to have
some good at least some poor guy is making some money.
There's some production of something. Yeah but at least there's some you know
there's some work involved where it's based on this our center is a great
I have no feelings for them.
I have this 50 story, acne-sivers and low-nossocers.
Acme, what's the name?
Acme is very popular.
One of my favorite names,
I mean, plumber, plumbing company.
- I have.
- I could have accuracy as a non-assucive.
And it's a talk that if our employees
who produce nothing,
you just administer sucking of people's blood.
- Is that how it is?
- Come on.
- For example, if you have a business,
you get that really easy.
Because they buy a lot, they sell five, four,
and maybe even more than 100% of it.
- You're the best?
- No, not the easiest.
Or is that anybody who's something black out of it.
They still have 100 or 100% of it.
You got a restriction on your mouth.
- Sure.
That's taking advantage of me.
- Is it true?
- It's not true.
- Isn't it true that some of the Arab banks themselves
that you know, the Arab banks that have been involved
in these cities?
- Everything.
the air body bomb.
The worst.
All the people they've loved, they've loved the best.
If you work in the factory, that means that you also commit this, and you help this bank
over it.
Do you have anything for a person?
If you work as a bartender, are you committing a sin?
That's the same question.
You don't drink yourselves.
I think the question is, do you have, do you drink it?
Do you have any, are you making money with use for yourself?
If you work in the bank and you have no money in the bank,
then you'll make no money from it yourself.
What's the job for you?
No, but you're ending, you're ending for all the users.
[inaudible]
I told you part of the banks, you invest in certain things.
Really, you don't have to study the gift.
There are chemical companies that produce, there are builders that produce,
hundreds of companies that produce.
Islamic economy is a productive economy.
Now you notice there is a statement here that God diminishes users and outman charities. Now God works in funny ways to ask their funny ways. And today I was using that exact to do for laughter in Arizona.
Oh, instead of Arizona last year started the lottery.
And for the first time in the history of Arizona,
there were hundreds of million dollar deficits in the budget.
Now those who designed the lottery, which are not productive,
gambling prohibited by his name by God, in the Quran and in the Bible.
When they put it down, the bear was supposed to earn money.
to come rich, reduce the burden of taxes on the people, etc., etc., but God diminishes
sinful earnings, gambling or users.
So the steadfast amount of $100 million debt doesn't make sense to them.
To us we understand the territory.
Because they resorted to a simple,
Germany's,
a bracket God's law,
whether it is usually or gambling,
they have to be a poor.
In the door of the paper,
we are making money on the paper.
(inaudible)
One thing that I learned today was that last week,
we had a program called Maibu, anybody saw that?
(inaudible)
It was about breakdown in Moriah
and
(inaudible)
The variety and how they live in the many movies, how they are accomplished, how many people mix them, and just took a corruption.
Oh no.
God was showing them in advance what I'm going to give you a piece now.
This happens today.
It's not an economic risk on the same year, but hold on.
I saw the seat in the house.
They showed me why there was no one going to go home from New York.
All right, so it happened to Canada.
New York's in Canada.
It's actually...
Don't take this with anything.
It's actually on tour.
Because God is doing all these things.
People out in New York.
[ Inaudible ]
>> 30 more.
>> 1-6-8.
1, 6, 8, in case, the verses 31 says, "Even if the Quran calls mountains to move or the
earth to shatter or the dead to speak, they will not believe."
That is because the whole matter is up to God.
Is it not time for the believers to give up on the disbelievers?
If God wins, he can guide all the people.
Those who just believe will continue to suffer disasters as a consequence of their work, or have them strike close to them until God's judgment comes.
Soon it never breaks as well. So, we have disasters, one after the other.
And the U.C.A.R.s hurricanes come and the A in for the elders.
Many places.
All comes mostly from so forth.
But back to this verse 27, it says, God, the ministry is using, and gambling.
You can add that to it.
Any sinful early.
If somebody steals something from someone,
around the bank,
Now what the paper appears like, they made money, but really they lose money.
They end up losing.
Any central ending, not the main system.
And we see these things in front of them.
Speaking of the state of Arizona, they will repeat the insurance part.
Are you ready?
You know what?
who repeat the insurance, the law, the law, the insurance.
(buzzer)
They want to even listen to us.
I wrote to the civil liberties union.
And I could see the liberties.
Yeah, of course, we're not very humble,
so they won't even consider it.
But God answers.
They will repeat that law.
Those who believe in work rights are just that observe the salah as they cut their
erectile pences with their mind.
They have nothing to fear nor where they grieve.
All you who believe, be aware of God and refrain from all forms of use of it if you are really
believers.
If you do not refrain, then accept, if you do not refrain, then expect a war from God and his messengers.
But if you repent, then you may keep your capital without inflicting justice or suffering in justice.
If the debtor is unable to pay, then wait for a better time.
If you give up the debtor's charity, it will be better for you if you only knew.
you be aware of the day when you return to God and what each show is retained for whatever
it is earned. No one will suffer in justice. Then speaking of the sin of usury and the
justice of God. So even if you have a bank account and you're money lender's account,
$25,000 or an IRA, you know, you've made a lot of, that money will just be lost is what
And there's no way you can win from a user.
And even if you win in this life, someday you're going to be held a college for.
You'll return.
You'll have to.
There's another-- sorry, in the end of the Quran, which talks about the rich being questioned
for what they did.
They'll actually be interrogated.
Right.
That's a good word.
They'll be interrogated for what they did.
The wealthy people.
I don't know which one of those agree?
It's right towards the end.
You know what's what I mean about the--
- There's one at the end.
- Almost at the end.
It ends with they will be interrogated
with what they've done.
- There's even a better one through a line where it says
there's more than two, but it would be heated up and head
and there would be good news.
There's one to report that we were sent.
- Yeah, hoarding.
You're preoccupied with hoarding
until you go into your graves,
indeed you will find out, yes you will, indeed find out.
If you could only find out now, you would envision hell,
you would envision it with an eye of certainty,
you will be asked about your hoarding.
So, interrogate it about your hoarding.
So this relates to that.
People will return to God and it will be
questioned about their use theory
and the excesses of wealth they have.
people unfortunately in this country
are worse than the dollar so much
that they become
very uncharitable, they can actually be charitable
to the country and serve it from the economic problems
they have, but you know, the biggest problem
in this country is the deficit.
100 big and bad of deficit,
unless 100 big and bad of deficit can be wiped out.
You know, we,
- Yes.
Now, 100 billion dollar deficit for 200 million people,
let's say America has 200 million people,
and the deficit is 100 billion dollars.
This means 500 dollars per person.
If the people are charitable to the government
and give the government 500 dollars each,
the deficit will be wiped out, okay,
as charities are concerned.
But they don't want to do it.
Now 500, I cannot pay 500 dollars on this.
Sam, far from the country, 500 dollars on this.
Sam, but there is a very rich question somewhere
who can pay for 10 of us, right?
5,000 dollars.
How many people in this country can give away
5,000 dollars to see if the country,
what I'm saying is with all the rich people
in this country, we can pay a million, 10 million,
500 dollars per head can be given to the government to solve the whole deficit problem with all the interest problems that go with it and everything else.
But as rich people who want interest to be hard, they can't stand to see it go down to 5% for them.
The reduces their ink, they have 200 million dollars, but that's not enough.
Somehow it increases their hunger or more money.
What about two...
It's amazing.
What about two seventy nine?
Expect a war.
There's God in his message.
That's right.
That's exactly what I mean by the hundred million dollar deficit in Arizona.
When they start to pollage, that's it, oh yeah?
You gonna make money?
Let's see about that.
Then the copper went down.
The copper, which is the source of income, I guess, is fake.
God said that war from God.
For God in this messenger means that at the time, Muhammad was alive, that he just actually
will out and make war on people who did use their India.
To say, "Expect the war from God in this messenger."
He says right there.
I mean, at that time...
The message is not confined to God.
Because anyone who speaks, anyone who speaks,
or God who speaks against the user,
if you speak on behalf of God, you will be against the user.
Right?
Right? You asked me against you, sir.
Yeah.
So, when you speak, when you speak on behalf of God, you're a messenger of God.
Businesses are not confined to a country.
I guess that most people interpret the word messenger in a foreign city
exclusively apply to more than one.
That's not the form of our divorce.
They ignore all the statements in ground that Muhammad is not the last Muslim place, the last
When I look at it in 33, you go 10 just 20, but there's nobody after them.
So in 33, the verse is 4 to 4, I believe.
8, 8, 8, 40.
Heads to 8-miners.
Heads to 8-miners are 5.
The father says, "Humbah is not the father of any of you.
He is a messenger of God and the final prophet.
He goes upon this Christian."
That's another big subject to branch.
But when we go back, it says, "Expect war from God and his message."
What's the difference in every group between the word "prophet,"
which is a lot of our school.
Prophet and message.
Messages are school of life.
And what is "prophetic"?
The Prophet is a man who wrote his troops before him.
Not now, it's an excuse to think.
- There's no government, it's an excuse to think more.
- Oh yeah, it's an excuse.
He's the last Prophet, this is the finest scriptures.
You see from the Bible.
He's the finest Prophet.
But every village has a message.
The Bible answers every generation, every village,
every community.
Never a message.
When you go on the market to meet somebody and think about God,
what's your God that owns your relationship with God at that point?
That's another subject for this.
Do I want to go on and show you come across almost,
because when it says a vague garden is messaging,
it doesn't say a vague garden is processed.
No?
Right.
You're going to come to many conclusions from that point.
It's a very important point.
Now, don't obey God and anyone who pleases the one God.
Any person who comes to you and says, "Worship God, I don't obey that."
Because this obeying means you're going to worship more than one God.
You're going to idolize someone beside God.
So if anyone comes and says to me, "What you are doing is wrong, you want to go to law class."
And then, and those people feel they make the market to the best market to make the same thing.
You know, and behind the pier, I tell you, you know, for example, you find the curse.
I have some excuses to, for example, that I cannot set a body and not say, "I make it even worse."
I have a similar question.
If you drive in these messages, expect more from driving in these messages.
[ Inaudible ]
and then you get some stuff, say, I need to get some stuff and you feel something, I need to get some stuff, and you have to try to get much more.
>> Yeah, so that person will be fighting this thing.
>> Yeah.
>> He'll declare war on this.
>> Right. Right.
>> But that person who's preaching God's message
is the message of God.
[ Inaudible ]
>> Nope.
They made the toughest deposit.
The final mess in Zuk and the final throw.
So is there any place in the Quran who it says he is the final mess in Zuk and the final throw?
Of course, they use this expression a lot to God of countries that he is the final mess in Zuk.
They made the talk.
So I'm a tensor in the Quran.
But it is not.
[ Inaudible ]
You know, learning, when you look at this sadness, and think about it.
So this country's deficit can do right now, but the rich people who can do it don't want to do it.
the government borrows the money to come with the deficit borrows from debt and gives them
15%, 20%.
Let us read the footnote 2, 275.
Since usually it's any fixed percentage of earnings in return from deposit or loan money.
Earnings that fluctuate to investment profits and losses do not constitute users.
It should be noted that the Quran can then only those who will take use of it.
While those who are forced by circumstance to be paid, usually are considered victims
other than sinners, as we see in verse 2a.
Look at verse 2a, it says, "If the debtor is unable to pay, then wait for a better time.
If you give up the debtor, the charity is good because of the youth, the only youth."
So the death of the person who took the death is a victim.
If you buy a house, the only way to buy a house is to have a mortgage on it and pay exuberant interest,
exorbitant interest, then you're a victim.
Of course the Haddis will tell you anybody who plays in this is also a symbol.
That's a heavy, that's wrong.
Any of you get some other differences
like if you play interest, it's just a half?
Thank you.
Good.
But if you have to play interest,
then you're okay.
>> Any other ideas or comments?
>> They're sort of a, I mean, between kind of deposit,
I suppose it's really used for you though.
The interest you're paid varies with the prevailing interest rate.
>> The student fixed?
>> Yeah, but it's fixed at a certain time.
>> Right. >> Yeah.
>> But actually, profit means there's a risk involved.
You could lose everything, you could double your money.
If you buy something and it probably goes up for some reason, that's great.
You made a good business decision.
Whereas you're guaranteed the money,
it's like you say it's not productive.
>> I remember we were discussing this the last time.
I had a long evening and after we discussed it,
the money came to me and this came to me and they said,
"You have money in saving, you can't keep on saving."
So, I wonder if it means part market.
Can you recommend something?
(laughing)
I just recommend something and the spats and zoopa.
And, let's go to the hospital,
and you have the last money in that transaction.
I didn't comment on the plan before, and that's what I've made it up to that.
I'm not interested.
I even think they're checking it out.
I think even though there's no use for you to be involved with checking it out.
I think they're bad.
Just because you're dealing with it back, the post office has a very good way of paying your bills.
You could buy a post on money or money.
and check sometime for your bills.
Your electric bill and your gas bill,
you can pay them at drumstores and--
- No, I think this is in the bank
as a deposit on your lighting and checks.
You're not earning tricks for sending.
It's worth it for your own life.
- But it's just my opinion, man.
It's like going into a barn, having a coke.
Well, it's okay to go to a barn.
- Okay, the question, the pocket will subject to a boss.
You can lose it.
I think it's going for you.
There are other ways of protecting your money,
besides carrying it in your pocket.
- It's not time though, to use the event
as long as you're not done in trips.
(crowd chattering)
- For a business, I guess it's a question of convenience.
- You're right though, I mean,
if I can avoid the amount of the work,
that one doesn't mean it's the best.
I'm the best, yeah?
You know you want to run back? I don't need to be. I'm a giant don't use the mess.
Very, very productive.
The US, this country is very red.
So much land, so many millions.
And the economy of the fix, the fix, and Islamic economy,
there's no interest.
You can charge the cost of handling your money.
And that's not fixed.
And so the stock market seems to be a good operation, not really.
Some people do use it for government.
Yeah, it's for the station.
Right.
People buy and send every day, this is the business.
It's the moment the money is from here to there.
That's government.
Because I mean it's all that kind of game and it's been going on.
These days, these high entities, these super high entities.
There's no work getting down, but they're not that much business going on.
Any love, productive, and gains of change,
so organic, go ahead and get it out.
And yesterday, productive.
When Mariam and Lisa put the money,
the market was giving us.
Of course, they put the money there,
because this market goes down.
(audience laughs)
Awesome.
But I assure you, God was making your talk to them
in many different ways.
- What about buying gold with pincers?
I don't know how that's acting, it's turning out.
And you need to mind to be the power of that.
- Very good.
- What if I called the year-adoy,
you would have made about 30% of it.
- Because when--
- That's not important, but the goal of the half
is to be as standard.
For example, 15 years ago for an ounce of gold
that can buy a good suit.
Today for an ounce of gold, it's still by a good suit.
The hours of gold, 15 years ago, was 35 dollars, and a good suit was 35 dollars.
Now, an hour of gold was 500 dollars, and a good suit was 500 dollars.
What I'm saying is that you're stabilizing your money.
What do you think is that kind of new?
You kept your 35 dollars, and you bought it from 15 years ago.
That'd be worth one tenth of what we really love.
or dome comes in. That's the problem of dome. That's the problem of dome. Actually, they do it. They spray it on tape. It's $35. It's free. On the engine. They do it.
(chatter)
Okay, let's see how the Quran gives us details of our life.
Where is the tube?
Right down by the same center.
What do you believe?
Can you tell us a lot about the compression?
Thank you.
Right down.
And it's vibrated down.
And it's vibrated right down.
Good.
(muffled speaking)
[ Inaudible ]
[inaudible]
(muffled speaking)
I like this guy.
So you may have to get this good out.
You know how I should share some part of this guy with him?
If you want to get the questions,
then you will be able to work with him.
If you're a third guy,
you have to be a third guy.
You have to be a third guy.
If you're a family,
then you'll try to develop a sense of a bond to the people.
You can trust each other in this manner.
They won't be a third guy.
behind the show.
(crowd murmuring)
(indistinct chatter)
[ Inaudible ]
(laughter)
- There's a really good example of people who say
you need to hide and sue that to the point of the law
and not cover it in the court.
- Yeah.
- How much of your detail?
- That is basically, yeah.
- Exactly.
- In any event, it says if you observe God,
God will teach you, so you don't have to go anywhere else,
even if there is something that he will discover.
That's what it is that they don't believe God, or it's just, this is all you need.
Okay, Jan, will I say something about that?
Or is it not?
I should.
Tell us about this faith.
Otherwise, the other I should.
(inaudible)
[ Inaudible ]
(muffled speaking)
I remember I was in California and I came to San Rafael Bridge. I didn't have the board. I wanted to go to the bottom. I wanted to go to the bottom.
I'm going to leave my bank, exactly the clock.
That's a bond.
I'd like to think of a bond that will make you come back
and give in the court to do some type of call.
You know, the left.
Right.
You're traveling in the desert somewhere,
and you don't have any money, and you need somebody to say,
"I need ten dollars."
And there are no crimes or witnesses or nothing. Just let this fellow. And you want ten thousand? So you can give him a jack. And the bond.
They take it?
No? Good enough.
You have no quarters in the room like you are working?
That's another story. But there you are today. That's just the bond I was thinking about.
I mean, how was he in the 19th?
I mean, how would anybody know if you were not
just a good member?
Oh, he's a good member.
Well, I know, but how did you say that after you invited me?
I was not afraid of you.
Yeah.
I know, I'm afraid of you.
I was coming from Sacramento, too, but you were
in the 20th.
I don't forget that, because I was a forest student
who was coming and doing that before.
I bet they did everything.
It would definitely look like this.
My money is another side, folks.
Now this, this combined with folks is very important.
You actually do it.
Any time you lend anybody money, unless you go on it,
you ride it down and you have witnesses.
Because we tend to forget, give somebody $20 and when the time comes, you say, "I don't
get a point, but for some reason we think it was a point of value."
A new friend, you can lose a friend this way, but it's written down.
But then there's no question about the number of witnesses.
The idea of one man and two women.
Why?
This is not what we call it, is it?
The idea is that if you have a man and a woman,
there is some putting around with this transaction.
The man can marry the woman, then you will talk,
because they do it one side.
If you have one man and two women,
even if polygamy applies and the land marriage,
The two women, these two women who had these dollars of guts,
that they would not agree on something
and anything, when it clogged, they'd take them off at this.
- Even if they're not married, you can talk.
- Listen, pal.
But this is God's law and we have to stick to it.
What do you do?
If you notice the beginning sentence,
all you who believe, one, you carry out the law
from such a different period, you shall write it down.
to money.
Have any other ideas, Johan?
What's up, Flak?
We're going to finish this tour of today, so I'll talk about it.
Was your head to finish it?
These are your permanent verses.
They happen to be your permanent verses.
285.
[ Inaudible ]
and what we do in the building in the jumping floor.
And it's known to be the biggest difference in a lot.
The name of the sister, the sister,
and the domestic.
The district will make no sense in the body,
in and out of this entity.
We are talking to them, and we are great.
Give us our doors to view the openness of their own.
Along with our own spiritual endurance,
it's been a tremendous concern of any right to work,
and just let it be a third or three-state.
All of those is not done, but where do we begin?
Our Earth, our North, and that this massive real world that we finally discovered, like those before, is finally discovered.
>> [INAUDIBLE]
(crowd murmuring)
(indistinct chatter)
Give us a call from this school, first.
(crowd murmuring)
(indistinct)
(indistinct said Government)
(muffled speaking)
[ Inaudible ]
(speaking in foreign language)
(muffled speaking)
[ Inaudible ]
(indistinct)
(muffled speaking)
[ Inaudible ]
[inaudible]
(muffled speaking)
[ Inaudible ]
[inaudible]
(indistinct chatter)
(muffled speaking)
[ Inaudible ]
[inaudible]
(indistinct chatter)
and then straight into school.
- Thank you.
- So they're on right.
- No, I'm sorry.
- This is straight and loud.
It's not straight.
We used to get our air.
- Hello.
(indistinct)
So we have another deterrent to live for difference
from that respect,
the central doctor from difference.
The people don't believe in God
or have some other gods beside God
and you don't enjoy that for dinner.
[ Inaudible ]
>> We forget the American space.
Thank God that God is forgiven.
[ Inaudible ]
Only the variables are forgiven.
I do wash because they're not forgiven.
Now, I'm talking about what you can,
the intent from either wash is to be shared,
and either wash is to be very, very white down,
once you're in your tent.
Either wash is not forgiven, if the person dies
and has dirt on either wash,
that's going to be forgiven.
[laughter]
(static)